<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../entries2html.xsl" ?>
<entry name="colorpalette" namespace="fn" type="widget" widgetnamespace="mobile" event-prefix="">
	<title>Colorpalette Widget</title>
	<desc>Displays an array of colors based on a given color.</desc>
	<longdesc>
		<h3>Colorpalette</h3>
		<p>The color palette widget displays a palette of colors given a single color. It constructs the palette by calculating dividing the hue spectrum evenly around the hue of the given color into as many parts as there are palette entries and constructing one color out of each of the calculated hue values, including the hue of the given color, while using the given color's saturation and lightness for the calculated colors.</p>
  	</longdesc>

	<added>0.2.0</added>
	<options>
		<option name="color" default="null" example-value="#f7b29a">
			<desc>The color that forms the basis for the palette. When you set the color, the <code>colors</code> option is set to a palette containing the color and hue-related siblings.</desc>
			<type name="String" />
		</option>
		<option name="showPreview" default="false" example-value="true">
			<desc>Whether to show the preview pane.</desc>
			<type name="Boolean" />
		</option>
		<option name="rows" default="2" example-value="3">
			<desc>The number of rows in which to display the pallette.</desc>
			<type name="Number" />
		</option>
		<option name="colors" default="#ff0000,#ff8000,#ffff00,#80ff00,#00ff00,#00ff80,#00ffff,#0080ff,#0000ff,#8000ff,#ff00ff,#ff0080" example-value="#aabbcc,#ddeeff,#001122,#334455,#667788,#99aabb,#012345,#6789ab,#cdef01,#02468a,#13579b,#112358">
			<desc>The colors to display in the palette. This is a comma-separated list of HTML RGB values. The number of colors in the palette will be adjusted to match the number of elements in the list. If the current color is the list, it will be selected.</desc>
			<type name="String" />
		</option>
	</options>
	<events>
		<event name="colorpalettecreate">
			<desc>Triggered when a colorpalette is created.</desc>
			<argument name="event" type="Event">
				<desc></desc>
			</argument>
			<argument name="ui" type="Object">
				<desc></desc>
			</argument>
		</event>
		<event name="colorchanged">
			<desc>Triggered when the selected color changes.</desc>
			<argument name="event" type="Event">
				<desc></desc>
			</argument>
		</event>
	</events>
	<methods>
		<method name="destroy">
			<desc>Destroys a colorpalette. This causes the DOM elemenent on which it is based to be restored to the state in which it was before the widget was created. Any DOM elements created as part of the widget will be destroyed.</desc>
		</method>
		<method name="refresh">
			<desc>Rebuilds the color palette.</desc>
		</method>
	</methods>
	<example>
		<desc>A basic example of a page with a colorpalette.</desc>
		<html><![CDATA[<div data-role="header">
		<h1>Web UI Framework Example</h1>
	</div>
	<div data-role="content">
		<div data-role="colorpalette"></div>
	</div>]]></html>
	</example>
	<category slug="widgets"/>
</entry>
